<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>LuxLeaks: Support Antoine Deltour</title>
  <subtitle>Antoine Deltour's support committee</subtitle>
  <id>https://support-antoine.org/</id>
  <link href="https://support-antoine.org/"/>
  <link href="https://support-antoine.org/en/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2018-09-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Antoine Deltour's support committee</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>AGM 2018:&lt;br/&gt; after the victory, the ending of the support committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/09/19/dissolution/"/>
    <id>https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/09/19/dissolution/</id>
    <published>2018-09-19T00:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2018-09-19T19:21:01+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Comité de soutien à Antoine</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 15, 2018, the Annual General Meeting of the Support Committee was held in Epinal (Centre Léo Lagrange) in front of about fifty people, many of whom had already attended previous meetings. A live webcast was also available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-09-19-ag.jpg" alt="Antoine, standing at the side of members, clapping"&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;© Comité de...&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 15, 2018, the Annual General Meeting of the Support Committee was held in Epinal (Centre Léo Lagrange) in front of about fifty people, many of whom had already attended previous meetings. A live webcast was also available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-09-19-ag.jpg" alt="Antoine, standing at the side of members, clapping" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;copy; Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour – CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="a-double-assessment-of-the-actions-carried-out"&gt;A double assessment of the actions carried out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The General Meeting was an opportunity to make a double assessment: an assessment of the past year achievements but, above all, an assessment of the actions carried out since the set up of the association in February 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at all the actions carried out since the creation of the association, some figures speak for themselves: 19 trips to Luxembourg to provide moral support for the defendants in the LuxLeaks trial (including 12 bus trips, rented by the association); 19 court reports and verdicts published on our website; 15 press releases; 11 information letters, each sent to more than 70,000 recipients; communications systematically published in French and English; numerous interviews given to the press; 25 meetings of the association's board; thousands of emails exchanged internally; a great activity on social networks… the Support Committee was very busy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These actions have been fruitful in terms of support given to Antoine: to date, more than 215,000 signatories of the petition; support from 71 civil society organizations and 477 public figures; success of the donation campaign with more than 2,500 donors and numerous sales of T-shirts and cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The financial statement for the past year is marked by a reduction in revenues (notably donations) compared to the previous year, while expenses continued to be high due to the payment of Antoine's lawyers for the appeal in cassation. The resulting negative result is largely offset by the cash accumulated over the past two years. In three years of existence, the cumulative income is around 90 000 €. The largest share of the expenditure covered legal costs. The remaining cash amounts to approximately €30,000 (which would have been used if the legal battle had to continue).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A detailed financial statement can be sent to anyone who requests it (contact@support-antoine.org).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-09-19-francois-antoine.jpg" alt="François Thiery presents the assessment of the Comité de soutien, Antoine stands at his side" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;François Thiery and Antoine Deltour&lt;br /&gt;Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour – CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="after-the-victory-dissolution-of-the-support-committee"&gt;After the victory, dissolution of the support committee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ordinary general meeting was immediately followed by an extraordinary general meeting aimed at dissolving the association, since its main objective of helping Antoine and financing his defence had been achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The participants voted unanimously in favour of the proposal, enshrined in the association's statutes, to redistribute the remaining assets of the Support Committee to several organisations working for fiscal justice and whistleblowers’ protection, in France and throughout the world. In particular, a donation is made to the Luxembourg Solidarity Committee for LuxLeaks defendants, with the objective to help funding Raphaël Halet's defence in the event of his continuing legal battle before the European Court of Human Rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The support committee Association's Board will now act as a care-taker until December 31st and will organise the redistribution of the 30,000 € according to the indications validated at the Extraordinary General Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="panel-discussion-to-update-on-whistleblowers-situation"&gt;Panel discussion to update on whistleblowers’ situation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evening continued with a panel discussion in which three guests discussed the situation of whistleblowers and the right to inform: Édouard Perrin (journalist, co-invicted in the LuxLeaks trial, president of the collective "Informer n'est pas un délit"), Glen Millot (Sciences Citoyennes association, leading the creation of the Whistleblowers' House) and Karim Ben Ali (whistleblower of ArcelorMittal illegal spills of acid in Florange, France).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three guests, with their specific experiences and commitments, all agreed that being a whistleblower is tough despite, in France, the recent implementation of a law which is supposed to protect them. From a legislative point of view, the good news about the start of the process for a whistleblowers’ directive at the European level is counterbalanced by the transposition of the trade secret directive into French law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is especially on a day-to-day basis that the situation of whistleblowers remains worrying, in front of judicial, economic or even social reprisals. Karim Ben Ali's testimony was striking, he summed up the situation as follows: "What is a whistleblower? it's above all a big nightmare…". This is why the future whistleblower's house, the creation of which is supported among others by the Sciences Citoyennes association, is important. And hence the choice of Antoine Support Committee to transfer a part of its residual funds to contribute to setting up this whistleblowers' house. We hope that this project will be completed by the end of the year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-09-19-table-ronde.jpg" alt="The fours participants of the discusssion panel, sitting" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Glen Millot, Karim Ben Ali, Antoine Deltour, and François Thiery&lt;br /&gt;&amp;copy;Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour – CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thanks-to-all-antoines-supporters"&gt;Thanks to all Antoine's supporters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antoine took the opportunity of the General Assembly to renew his thanks to all the people who, in one way or another, have supported him for more than three years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I find it wonderful that my action has spawned a collective momentum. Without this huge surge of solidarity, I wouldn’t have emerged unscathed from this long legal battle. I’m immensely grateful to all those who were right to believe in it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dissolution of the Support Committee marks the end of a fight, that of Antoine Deltour to obtain an acquittal during the LuxLeaks trial. But the struggle is not over! Antoine and the members of the Support Committee called on everyone to continue the mobilisation for tax justice, and so that all of us, potential whistleblowers, can continue to defend the public interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-09-19-patchwork.jpg" alt="Patchwork of pictures shot during the various mobilization events, with a legend saying “Success of the mobilisation, a big THANKS to you all!”" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;the Support Committee was very busy!&lt;br /&gt;&amp;copy;Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour – CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="press-coverage"&gt;Press coverage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le Quotidien&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.lequotidien.lu/grande-region/dissolution-du-comite-de-soutien-objectif-atteint-pour-antoine-deltour/"&gt;Dissolution du comité de soutien : « Objectif atteint » pour Antoine Deltour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vosges TV&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.vosgestelevision.tv/info/info/Combat-continue-1KJ6O9VLt9.html"&gt;Le combat continue&lt;/a&gt; (reportage)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vosge Matin&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.vosgesmatin.fr/edition-d-epinal/2018/06/18/luxleaks-le-comite-de-soutien-d-antoine-deltour-dissous-apres-trois-ans-de-lutte-pour-plus-de-justice-fiscale"&gt;LuxLeaks : le comité de soutien d’Antoine Deltour dissous après trois ans de lutte pour plus de justice fiscale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;WOXX Magazine&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.woxx.lu/luxleaks-clap-final-pour-antoine-deltour/"&gt;Luxleaks : Clap final pour Antoine Deltour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dissolution of the Support Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/06/15/pr-dissolution/"/>
    <id>https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/06/15/pr-dissolution/</id>
    <published>2018-06-15T00:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-15T22:19:28+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Antoine's support committee</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/docs/pr/2018-06-15-pr-EN-dissolution.pdf"&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-file-pdf-o"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span&gt;PDF version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="press-release"&gt;Press Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Épinal, June 15, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Friday, June 15, 2018, the Support Committee to Antoine Deltour met in Épinal for its Annual General Meeting, followed by a Special Meeting approving its dissolution. Antoine Deltour was formally...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/docs/pr/2018-06-15-pr-EN-dissolution.pdf"&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-file-pdf-o"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span&gt;PDF version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="press-release"&gt;Press Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Épinal, June 15, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Friday, June 15, 2018, the Support Committee to Antoine Deltour met in Épinal for its Annual General Meeting, followed by a Special Meeting approving its dissolution. Antoine Deltour was formally and fully acquitted on May 15 by the Luxembourg Court of Appeal for his role as a whistleblower in the LuxLeaks case, a scandal that had spectacularly shed light on multinationals’ systemic tax evasion schemes within the European Union itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antoine Deltour Support Committee was set up more than three years ago, first in its early form by Antoine's relatives and other sympathizers, then established as an association (under the 1901 French Act) on February 28, 2015. The Committee gathered tremendous and enthusiastic civic support. Representing several hundred members, we obtained the support of 215,000 signatories of the “Support Antoine Deltour!” petition. The campaign was backed by 71 organizations, 477 personalities and thousands of donors. All of them were convinced of the merits of Antoine's action for tax justice, and of the need to better protect whistleblowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the meeting, Antoine once again thanked all these supporters: &lt;em&gt;“I find it wonderful that my action has spawned a collective momentum. Without this huge surge of solidarity, I wouldn’t have emerged unscathed from this long legal battle. I’m immensely grateful to all those who were right to believe in it!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The General Assembly was an opportunity to review the work of the Support Committee since its setup: 19 trips to Luxembourg to provide moral support to the defendants during the various hearings of the LuxLeaks trial; equal number of hearing reports published on our website; 15 press releases; 11 newsletters, each sent to more than 70,000 recipients; all communications systematically published in French and English; numerous interviews; 25 work meetings; thousands of emails exchanged internally; a great activity on social networks… we have not been sitting on our hands! We would like to warmly thank all those who have contributed, directly or indirectly, in any way whatsoever, to supporting Antoine at our side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Civic solidarity and donation campaigns also enabled us to fully fund Antoine's defense for this marathon trial, representing a total of over 90,000 €. The remaining assets of the Support Committee, some €30,000, will be redistributed to several organizations fighting for tax justice and whistleblower protection, in France and around the world. We also made a donation to the Luxembourg Solidarity Committee for the LuxLeaks defendants, with the mission of helping to fund Raphaël Halet's defense in the event of his continuing legal battle before the European Court of Human Rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dissolution of the Support Committee marks the end of a fight that of Antoine Deltour to obtain an acquittal during the LuxLeaks trial. But the struggle is not over! We call on everyone to continue to mobilize for tax justice, and so that all of us, potential whistleblowers, can continue to defend the public interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="press-contact"&gt;Press Contact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour&lt;br /&gt;
Centre Léo Lagrange&lt;br /&gt;
BP 1006&lt;br /&gt;
88050 EPINAL Cedex 9&lt;br /&gt;
France&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email: &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#045;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;"&gt;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#045;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/support_antoine"&gt;@support_antoine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Support-Antoine/388682861307176"&gt;Support Antoine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Verdict of the 2nd appeal trial</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/05/15/pr-appeal2-verdict/"/>
    <id>https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/05/15/pr-appeal2-verdict/</id>
    <published>2018-05-15T00:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-15T22:19:25+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Antoine's support committee</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/docs/pr/2018-05-15-pr-EN-luxleaks-appeal2-verdict.pdf"&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-file-pdf-o"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span&gt;PDF version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="press-release"&gt;Press Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Épinal, May 15, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday 15 May at 3 pm, the Luxembourg Court of Appeal released its judgment on the second appeal trial for the whistleblower Antoine Deltour. This trial, the only hearing of which was held on 27...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/docs/pr/2018-05-15-pr-EN-luxleaks-appeal2-verdict.pdf"&gt;&lt;i class="fa fa-file-pdf-o"&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;span&gt;PDF version&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="press-release"&gt;Press Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Épinal, May 15, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday 15 May at 3 pm, the Luxembourg Court of Appeal released its judgment on the second appeal trial for the whistleblower Antoine Deltour. This trial, the only hearing of which was held on 27 March, followed Antoine’s victory before the Court of Cassation, which, on 11 January, quashed the previous sentence of 6 months suspended prison and 1,500 euros fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, as the Court of Cassation did before it, the Court of Appeal has fully recognized Antoine Deltour as a whistleblower within the meaning of the European Court of Human Rights. &lt;strong&gt;Antoine is therefore fully acquitted on all charges concerning the copying and use of the LuxLeaks documents&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This second appeal trial was also intended to judge an anecdotal part of the case: like many employees on departure, Antoine copied internal training documents. It is when looking for these slideshows that he found the tax rulings at the origin of the LuxLeaks. He never used or communicated these training documents. For these facts, the Court of Appeal records the breach of law, but &lt;strong&gt;decides to withhold the sentence&lt;/strong&gt;. It is the best result possible, so it’s an undeniable victory! The acquittal of the LuxLeaks case –which was the real issue at stake in this trial– will comfort any citizen witnessing ethically reprehensible practices and who would decide to also blow the whistle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antoine Deltour has expressed his “immense gratitude to the many people and organizations who supported [him] in this ordeal and without whom [he] would not have been able to lead this fight. While [he has] been fortunate enough to have broad support, many less visible whistleblowers experience great difficulties”. A more protective legal framework is therefore essential. The draft European directive for the protection of whistleblowers is an encouraging signal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond his personal case, Antoine is aware that his trial has helped the European public debate on tax justice, whistleblowers’ protection and freedom of information to advance. In a context where tax evasion remains a scourge in Europe and worldwide, informing citizens is an essential prerequisite for real change. Antoine Deltour wishes “a happy outcome for the two co-defendants in the LuxLeaks case, Édouard Perrin and Raphaël Halet, whose judicial journey is not over”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The General Assembly for the dissolution of the support committee to Antoine Deltour will be held on Friday June 15th at 8pm at the Léo Lagrange centre in Épinal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="press-contact"&gt;Press Contact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour&lt;br /&gt;
Centre Léo Lagrange&lt;br /&gt;
BP 1006&lt;br /&gt;
88050 EPINAL Cedex 9&lt;br /&gt;
France&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email: &lt;a href="&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#045;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;"&gt;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#117;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#116;&amp;#045;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/support_antoine"&gt;@support_antoine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Facebook: &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Support-Antoine/388682861307176"&gt;Support Antoine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>LuxLeaks Trial:&lt;br/&gt; New Appeal Hearing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/03/28/appeal2/"/>
    <id>https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/03/28/appeal2/</id>
    <published>2018-03-28T00:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-15T22:19:25+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Antoine’s support committee</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id="a-whistleblower-on-trial"&gt;A whistleblower on trial&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Tuesday, March 27 was the final hearing of the LuxLeaks trial, before a newly constituted Court of Appeal. This hearing followed the decision of the Court of Cassation on January 11 to overturn the previous Court of Appeal...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="a-whistleblower-on-trial"&gt;A whistleblower on trial&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Tuesday, March 27 was the final hearing of the LuxLeaks trial, before a newly constituted Court of Appeal. This hearing followed the decision of the Court of Cassation on January 11 to overturn the previous Court of Appeal’s judgment, which had sentenced Antoine to a 6-month suspended jail time and a € 1,500 fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge of today’s hearing is to take into account the full recognition of the whistleblower status notified by the Court of Cassation, while dealing with the case of the training documents copied by Antoine when he left PriceWatehouseCoopers (PwC) in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-03-28-penning-antoine-bourdon.jpg" alt="Antoine answering to journalists, after the hearing, between Mr. Philippe Penning and Mr. William Bourdon." /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;copy; Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour – CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-prosecutor-sets-the-scene"&gt;The Prosecutor sets the scene&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hearing began with prosecutor John Petry. The latter summarises the Court of Cassation’s decision, emphasising that there is no longer any need to rule on the facts relating to LuxLeaks (disclosure of tax rulings), for which Antoine is protected by the whistleblower status recognised by Luxembourg’s highest court. John Petry seems, however, to regret this decision, describing it as “very generous”, and insists at length on the fact that only the a posteriori publication of the tax rulings makes it possible to justify their theft…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The copy of the training documents is the only action to be judged. Antoine copied them when he left PwC, at the same time as the tax rulings. The prosecutor recommends a reduction of the March 2017 appeal sentence (a 6-month suspended jail time and a € 1,500 fine), reduced to a simple fine. He also suggests, almost facetiously, to reduce the symbolic euro of damages for the civil party to 50 symbolic cents!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="plaintiffs-arguments"&gt;Plaintiff’s arguments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then comes Mr. Hansen, representing the PwC civil party. Without concessions, Mr. Hansen seeks to demonstrate that the copy of documents constitutes a real steal of the company’s know-how. He details the case of 7 training documents Antoine would have accessed during his last navigation on the PwC server. According to the plaintiff, Antoine wanted to share these documents with competitors! Clearly stung by &lt;a href="https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/01/11/pr-cassation-verdict/"&gt;Antoine’s reaction to the cassation judgment&lt;/a&gt;, he recalls that the offence should not be taken lightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-03-28-bourdon-antoine.jpg" alt="Antoine standing in the court room, chatting with Mr. William Bourdon." /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;copy; Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour – CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="antoines-defense"&gt;Antoine’s defense&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antoine briefly took the floor, recalling in particular that “the Court of Cassation’s judgment is the consecration of a fight carried out for several years, of which [he is] very proud”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antoine’s speech is followed by the one of his first lawyer, Mr. William Bourdon, whom the President of the Court of Appeal interrupted and invited to be concise. Bourdon recalls that Antoine was already in a position to blow the whistle when he copied the documents, and that the Court of Cassation’s decision cannot be reduced to a simple retroactive law mechanism. Bourdon incisively underlines the “indecency” of the prosecution’s obstinacy, whom he describes as “bad losers, who try to reach a conviction at all costs”. He invites the Court to take a historic decision, and concludes by congratulating Antoine, who “has remained the same since the first day: simple, honest, modest, impeccable”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Philippe Penning, Antoine’s Luxembourg lawyer, then takes the stand. He notes that only 1 of the 7 training documents previously described by the plaintiff as having been copied by Antoine was present on his harddrive. Moreover, the number of pages copied presented by PwC does not correspond to reality. Penning then recalls - backed by several studies! - that copying training documents when leaving a company is a very common practice. In order not to harm Antoine’s career, the defense requested the non-registration of the judgment in Antoine’s criminal record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PwC’s lawyers reply in Luxemburgish (or German?), thus preventing Antoine from understanding and thus from participating in the debate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-03-28-support1.jpg" alt="A group of supporters holding a banner, in the rain, in front of the courthouse" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;copy; Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour – CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="judgment-on-may-15"&gt;Judgment on May 15&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The President of the Court of Appeal announces that he defers decision of the verdict. The judgment will be delivered on May 15, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This final hearing marks the end of the LuxLeaks trial in Luxembourg. Antoine steps out of the courthouse, always accompanied by about thirty members of his Support Committee, who continuously accompanied him until the end of this judicial marathon. Thanks to them! Thank you all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-03-28-support2.jpg" alt="A few supporters, holding banner and signs, in the courtyard" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;copy; Comité de soutien à Antoine Deltour – CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="press-coverage"&gt;Press coverage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luxembourg Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://luxtimes.lu/luxembourg/33314-luxleaks-whistle-blower-set-for-final-court-battle"&gt;LuxLeaks whistle-blower set for final court battle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;AFP (via Le Monde)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.lemonde.fr/evasion-fiscale/article/2018/03/27/luxleaks-le-lanceur-d-alerte-antoine-deltour-juge-en-appel-au-luxembourg_5276864_4862750.html"&gt;« LuxLeaks » : le lanceur d’alerte Antoine Deltour jugé en appel au Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt; (in French)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;L’Essentiel&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.lessentiel.lu/fr/luxembourg/story/Amende-revue-a-la-baisse-pour-Antoine-Deltour-12754817"&gt;Amende revue à la baisse pour Antoine Deltour&lt;/a&gt; (in French)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;L’Est Républicain&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.estrepublicain.fr/actualite/2018/03/28/luxleaks-decision-le-15-mai"&gt;LuxLeaks : décision le 15 mai&lt;/a&gt; (in French)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le Quotidien&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.lequotidien.lu/a-la-une/antoine-deltour-rejuge-a-luxembourg-une-amende-moins-elevee-reclamee/"&gt;Antoine Deltour rejugé à Luxembourg : une amende moins élevée réclamée&lt;/a&gt; (in French)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Luxemburger Wort&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.wort.lu/fr/luxembourg/luxleaks-dernieres-passes-d-armes-a-la-cour-5abb42f1c1097cee25b8615e"&gt;Luxleaks: dernières passes d'armes à la Cour&lt;/a&gt; (in French)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paperjam&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://paperjam.lu/news/derniere-passe-darmes-entre-deltour-et-pwc"&gt;Dernière passe d’armes entre Deltour et PwC&lt;/a&gt; (in French)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;RTL&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://5minutes.rtl.lu/laune/actu/1156435.html"&gt;Seule une amende a été requise à l'encontre d'Antoine Deltour&lt;/a&gt; (in French)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>LuxLeaks Trial:&lt;br/&gt; next step on March 27th</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/02/11/next-step/"/>
    <id>https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/02/11/next-step/</id>
    <published>2018-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-15T22:19:25+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Antoine's support committee</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On January 11st, the Luxembourg Court of Cassation fully recognised Antoine Deltour as a whistleblower and cancelled his conviction. This &lt;a href="https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/01/11/pr-cassation-verdict/"&gt;historical victory&lt;/a&gt; comes after more than three years of mobilisation. Thanks to those who helped Antoine! His...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On January 11st, the Luxembourg Court of Cassation fully recognised Antoine Deltour as a whistleblower and cancelled his conviction. This &lt;a href="https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/01/11/pr-cassation-verdict/"&gt;historical victory&lt;/a&gt; comes after more than three years of mobilisation. Thanks to those who helped Antoine! His judicial marathon is not over yet. He’s referred back to the Court of Appeal on &lt;strong&gt;March 27th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src="/images/news/2018-02-11-antoine.jpg" alt="Antoine, smiling, raising his right hand to thank the supporters outside the courthouse" /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Antoine Deltour, at the first appeal trial&lt;br /&gt;© Annie Gruchy – All rights reserved&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id="rendezvous-at-the-court-of-appeal-on-march-27th"&gt;Rendezvous at the Court of Appeal on March 27th&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antoine is not yet fully acquitted. He is referred back to the Court of Appeal, first to acknowledge his acquittal, due to his now recognised whistleblower status. He will also be judged for an anecdotal part of the case: as many employees leaving their job, Antoine copied training slides. Incidentally, Antoine came across the tax rulings resulting in the LuxLeaks revelations as he was looking for these slides. He never used or gave them. If he is condemned, this will be a very little consolation for the plaintiff PwC. &lt;strong&gt;Rendezvous on Tuesday March 27th, at the Luxembourg Court of Appeal&lt;/strong&gt;. We hope to see a full acquittal soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="halet-on-the-road-to-the-echr"&gt;Halet on the road to the ECHR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The victory in the Court of cassation is unfortunately to be tempered by the confirmation of the fine already sentenced to Raphaël Halet. During the spring appeal trial, the judge had not recognised Halet's whistleblower status. Halet announced his decision to refer his case to the European Court of Human Rights (ECHR) in order to get the recognition that he only acted as a whistleblower. We support his fight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="journalist-douard-perrin-sentenced-to-pay-3000-euros-to-pwc"&gt;Journalist Édouard Perrin sentenced to pay 3,000 euros to PwC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On February 7th, the Court of Metz (France) rejected summary proceedings filed by Raphaël Halet and journalist Édouard Perrin, against of the prosecutor’s view. Perrin is even ordered to pay PwC 3,000 euros. Perrin, joined by Halet, had summoned PwC Luxembourg in summary proceedings for violation of the confidentiality of journalistic sources. The Metz Court judgment is &lt;strong&gt;a serious attack to protection of sources and press freedom&lt;/strong&gt;. Édouard Perrin has announced that he will appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="soon-a-general-annual-meeting"&gt;Soon a General Annual Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antoine’s support committee was set up early 2015 to help Antoine, an exemplary citizen that had to be protected. Thanks to your support, commitment and donations, the mission has already been accomplished. This support will continue until the proceedings against Antoine come to an end. The support will then take new forms to be defined together soon, during the next general annual meeting of the association. The date of the General Annual Meeting will be set once the judge in Luxembourg states the new judgment date (a priori announced at the end of the March 27th hearing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="press-coverage-verdict-of-the-court-of-cassation"&gt;Press coverage: verdict of the Court of Cassation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In English and non-French languages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deutsche Welle&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.dw.com/en/luxleaks-luxembourg-court-overturns-verdict-against-whistleblower/a-42105300"&gt;LuxLeaks: Luxembourg court overturns verdict against whistleblower&lt;/a&gt; (with video)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/luxleaks-court-overturns-verdict-against-whistleblower/"&gt;Court overturns verdict against LuxLeaks whistleblower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;EU Observer&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://euobserver.com/justice/140518"&gt;LuxLeaks whistleblower Deltour acquitted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;New Europe&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.neweurope.eu/article/luxembourgs-highest-overturns-luxleaks-whistle-blower-conviction/"&gt;Luxembourg’s highest overturns LuxLeaks whistle-blower conviction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;El diaro&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.eldiario.es/politica/Justicia-luxemburguesa-condena-filtrador-LuxLeaks_0_728277394.html"&gt;La Justicia luxemburguesa anula la condena contra un “filtrador” de LuxLeaks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In French:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;France 3 Lorraine&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/388682861307176/videos/928907987284658/"&gt;Journal télévisé&lt;/a&gt; (vidéo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;L’Obs&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.nouvelobs.com/justice/20180111.OBS0508/luxleaks-antoine-deltour-est-reconnu-dans-ses-droits.html"&gt;LuxLeaks : "Antoine Deltour est reconnu dans ses droits"&lt;/a&gt; (interview de William Bourdon)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le Figaro&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.lefigaro.fr/international/2018/01/11/01003-20180111ARTFIG00207-luxleaks-antoine-deltour-reconnu-comme-lanceur-d-alerte-par-la-justice.php"&gt;LuxLeaks : Antoine Deltour reconnu comme lanceur d'alerte par la justice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le Monde&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.lemonde.fr/evasion-fiscale/article/2018/01/11/luxleaks-la-condamnation-d-un-des-lanceurs-d-alerte-francais-annulee-en-cassation-au-luxembourg_5240227_4862750.html"&gt;LuxLeaks : la condamnation d’un des lanceurs d’alerte français annulée en cassation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le Point&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.lepoint.fr/justice/luxleaks-la-cour-de-cassation-annule-la-condamnation-du-lanceur-d-alerte-antoine-deltour-11-01-2018-2185601_2386.php"&gt;LuxLeaks : la Cour de cassation annule la condamnation du lanceur d'alerte Antoine Deltour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Libération&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.liberation.fr/france/2018/01/11/le-lanceur-d-alerte-antoine-deltour-obtient-gain-de-cause-en-cassation_1621729"&gt;Le lanceur d'alerte Antoine Deltour obtient gain de cause en cassation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marianne&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.marianne.net/economie/luxleaks-antoine-deltour-reconnu-comme-lanceur-d-alerte-par-la-cour-de-cassation-du"&gt;Luxleaks : Antoine Deltour reconnu comme lanceur d'alerte par la Cour de cassation du Luxembourg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mediapart&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.mediapart.fr/journal/economie/110118/pour-le-luxembourg-antoine-deltour-est-enfin-un-vrai-lanceur-d-alerte"&gt;Pour le Luxembourg, Antoine Deltour est enfin un vrai lanceur d’alerte&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;PaperJam&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://paperjam.lu/news/antoine-deltour-reconnu-lanceur-dalerte-a-100"&gt;Antoine Deltour reconnu lanceur d’alerte à 100%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paris Match (Belgique)&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://parismatch.be/actualites/societe/106673/affaire-luxleaks-antoine-deltour-reconnu-lanceur-alerte-justice"&gt;LuxLeaks : Antoine Deltour enfin reconnu lanceur d’alerte par la justice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;RTBF&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="https://www.rtbf.be/info/societe/detail_affaire-luxleaks-la-condamnation-d-antoine-deltour-annulee-en-cassation-au-luxembourg?id=9808235"&gt;Affaire Luxleaks: la condamnation du lanceur d'alerte Antoine Deltour est annulée&lt;/a&gt; (Vidéo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rue89&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.rue89strasbourg.com/cour-de-cassation-luxembourg-annulation-condamnation-antoine-deltour-130093"&gt;La Cour de cassation du Luxembourg annule une condamnation d’Antoine Deltour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tageblatt&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.tageblatt.lu/headlines/linterview-avec-antoine-deltour/"&gt;« C’est la course vers le bas »&lt;/a&gt; (interview d’Antoine)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;WOXX&lt;/em&gt; - &lt;a href="http://www.woxx.lu/luxleaks-diviser-pour-mieux-regner/"&gt;Luxleaks : Diviser pour mieux régner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>That‘s it, I won! But is it really a victory?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/01/13/reaction-antoine/"/>
    <id>https://support-antoine.org/en/blog/2018/01/13/reaction-antoine/</id>
    <published>2018-01-13T00:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2018-06-15T22:19:25+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Antoine Deltour</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This statement was originally published by Antoine on 11 January 2017 on Facebook (in French). We cross-pubished it here as an op-ed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That‘s it, I won! Although, usually, when you win, it’s in a game or a battle… Though I didn‘t play, nor fight...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This statement was originally published by Antoine on 11 January 2017 on Facebook (in French). We cross-pubished it here as an op-ed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That‘s it, I won! Although, usually, when you win, it’s in a game or a battle… Though I didn‘t play, nor fight. I only acted as a citizen. Is it really a victory not to be convicted when one only acted as citizen? Anyway, I‘m very happy about that, really, it‘s a relief. And I am very grateful to the many supporters, it’s a collective victory. But in my opinion, this victory is only the mere application of the law, and this is precisely what we have been asking for since the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;My judicial marathon is not over yet. I am referred back to the Court of Appeal. But I will go there serenely, accused of a minor ultra-peripheral part of the case. Indeed, when I left PwC, I not only copied the tax rulings (&lt;em&gt;LuxLeaks&lt;/em&gt;), but also some training slides. Everyone does that, and I actually never opened these files, and who cares?! Maybe I‘ll get a residual conviction for this. I could also be arrested for going through a red traffic light on my way to the court. If that‘s all they can get, I‘m a fair player and I‘ll accept the sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Also, my happiness is tempered by the rejection of Raphel Halet‘s appeal. According to the Luxembourg justice, he would not be a whistleblower because of the insufficient interest of the documents he revealed. These documents, however, were the basis of one full “Cash Investigation” newsmagazine TV program. And they target companies like Ikea and Amazon that are currently under the investigations of the European Commission. I therefore express my solidarity with Raphael. He will now continue the fight before the European Court of Human Rights. We‘ll follow this closely.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It is hardly known but a European whistleblowers protection already exists. It‘s the case law of the European Court of Human Rights. In my case, it took a very long road to get to its full application (and it’s not yet finished). We had to go through three judicial authorities and to collect many anonymous support donations (thank you!). In order to avoid such difficulties for future whistleblowers, especially those who are less visible and unfortunately without the same strong support, it is urgent to that a European directive is adopted. Such a directive would protect whistleblowers much more directly than under the European Convention on Human Rights. Members of the European Parliament are already pushing very hard in this direction. We must now counter the European Commission and some Member States’ inertia. For this, public pressure is essential.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Finally, now that we are almost done discussing the whistleblowers’ situation, we may finally deal with the core content of the case. And as a matter of fact I have a few thoughts to share in this context:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;LuxLeaks 2&lt;/em&gt; revelations of December 2014 fell into oblivion, even if they involve ALL major audit firms, including PwC‘s competitors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Luxembourg brilliantly mastered its post-_LuxLeaks_ communication (“these practices are over, we drastically progressed since then”) but continues to oppose corporate tax harmonization, against the very views of J.C. Juncker himself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Despite some progress towards tax justice, corporate tax revenues in Europe continue to vanish like the ice pack at the North Pole. And the profits of multinationals are rising like sea level in the Maldives. This race to the bottom results from tax competition.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The repeated scandals, and especially the &lt;em&gt;Paradise Papers&lt;/em&gt;, make me progressively doubt that we will be able to put all this in order one day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Finally, in my opinion, we’d better spare the bandwidth to work instead on limiting the damages and building the future. Indeed, the human species cannot continue to destroy its own living environment for long without getting a brutal call to order.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Sorry about this last off-topic, but in the end, that‘s what this case brought me: a tiny bit of fame to keep on alerting on the issues that are of direct concern to me.&lt;br /&gt;
Happy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Antoine Deltour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
